Nuclear Age History and Humanities Center Records UA027
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Nuclear Age History and Humanities Center Records
1986 -- 1992
1970 -- 1993
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Nuclear Age History and Humanities Center
UA027
7.2 Linear Feet 6 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in seven series: NAHHC Subject Files (R); Global Classroom Project Publicity Files (B); Martin Sherwin Subject Files (W); Fundraising Subject Files (G); Moscow Travel (Y); Daily Logs; and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
DCA received the bulk of these records in December 2006. A small portion were subsequently transferred to DCA in 2007.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, proposals, drafts, Dr. Martin Sherwin's personal correspondence and research notes relating to the founding of the NAHHC, and various programs the center organized and participated in. The bulk of the material in the collection is from 1986 - 1992. Documentation relating to the GCP includes transcripts, course outlines, slides, photographs, and video tapes, as well as records from student trips to Moscow and the US from 1988 to 1992, and a video tape of the Moscow student trip in 1988.
Biographical / Historical
The Nuclear Age History and Humanities Center (NAHHC) was established at Tufts University in October 1986. It was the first academic center in the nation dedicated to the interdisciplinary study of the nuclear era. It sponsored research projects and offered programs discussing nuclear conflicts and their peaceful resolutions leading to nuclear disarmament. The NAHHC also helped organize different University Presidents Conferences. At these conferences international university presidents discussed nuclear issues. NAHHC is best known for its Global Classroom Project (GCP), also called the "Space Bridge" or "Tufts - Moscow Space Bridge." GCP was a course jointly taught between Moscow State University, and Tufts University via television and satellite technology. From 1988 to 1992, NAHHC produced eleven GCPs that allowed direct, frank discussions between students and Russian and American panelists from various national and international institutions. Martin Sherwin, founding director of the NAHHC, established the GCP in 1987. A professor of History at Tufts, Sherwin and Evgeny P. Velikhov of the USSR Academy of Science, jointly taught the course, offered regularly at both universities, using one syllabus and meeting four times a semester via satellite. The NAHHC received national and international acclaim for its innovative curriculum.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes; Foreign affairs
- NAHHC General Subject Files, 1985 -- 1993; 1986 -- 1992; UA027.001; 4.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials from the NAHHC. The bulk of the records deal with organizing, implementing, and broadcasting the GPC nationally and internationally. Included are also records from various University Presidents Conferences. Some records contain confidential information and are restricted. For related material, see also series 2.
  Arrangement
  Folders are arranged alphabetically. Originally, folders were filed according to a color coded system. The color tabs are indicated in parenthesis after the original folder title. Folders in this series were color coded red (R).
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - 3rd Asian Pacific Conference (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Alumni/Parents Interest (R), 1989; UA027.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Brown, George E. (US Rep) (R), 1987; UA027.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Carter Center (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Congrats and Compliments (R), 1989; UA027.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - [Dartmouth Moscow Exchange], 1989; UA027.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Erofeev-Russian TV and Radio (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Future TPC (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - GCP 1 (R), 1986 -- 1987; UA027.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - GCP I [Transcripts], 1987; UA027.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - GCP 2 (R), 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - GCP II [Transcripts], 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #2, Video Tape], 1988; UA027.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    This is a surrogate folder, for preservation reasons the VHS tape is stored in box 4 of the collection.
  - [GCP #2, Video Tape], 1988; UA027.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #2, Video Tape], 1988; UA027.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - GCP 3 (R), 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - GCP III [Transcripts], 1988; UA027.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #3, Video Tape], 1988; UA027.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    This is a surrogate folder, for preservation purposes the VHS is stored seperately in box 4 of the collection.
  - GCP 4 (R), 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - GCP IV [Transcripts], 1988; UA027.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #4, Video Tape], 1988; UA027.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
    This is a surrogate folder, for preservation purposes the VHS tape is stored seperately in box 4 of the collection.
  - GCP 5 (R), 1988; UA027.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - GCP V [Transcripts], 1988; UA027.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #5, Video Tape, Tape 1], 1988; UA027.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - GCP 6 (R), 1989; UA027.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - GCP IV [Transcripts], 1989; UA027.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #6, Video Tape, Tape 1], 1989; UA027.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #6, Video Tape, Tape 2], 1989; UA027.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - GCP 7 (R), 1989; UA027.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #7 - Admission Ticket], 1989; UA027.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - GCP VII [Transcripts], 1989; UA027.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - GCP 8 (R), 1990; UA027.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - GCP VIII [Transcripts], 1990; UA027.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #8, Video Tape], 1990; UA027.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - GCP 9 (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #9, Video Tape, April 20, 1991], UA027.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #9, Video Tape, Tape 1, April 26, 1991], UA027.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - GCP 10 (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #10, Video Tape, Edited Version], 1991; UA027.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - GCP 11 (R), 1992; UA027.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #11 - Briefing Book], 1992; UA027.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #11 - Letter re: Junior Achievement Program], 1992; UA027.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #11 - Slides], 1992; UA027.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
    This is a surrogate folder, for preservation purposes the box of slides is stored seperately in box 4 of the collection.
  - [GCP #11 - Thank You Notes], 1992 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #11, Video Tape], 1992; UA027.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - [GCP #11, Video Tape, Edited Version], 1992; UA027.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Gosteleradio (R), 1987 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Gosteleradio GCP Letter, 1987 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - IntelSat (R), 1988; UA027.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - [Institute on Global Conflict & Cooporation, UC San Diego], 1986 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Interpreter Information (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - IREX - GCP (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - The Learning Channel (R), 1990 -- 1991; UA027.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - MCET - GCP (R), 1987; UA027.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Mendeleev Institute (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
    75 years from the date of creation.
    This folder contains confidential information (passport numbers) and should be checked by staff before use by a researcher.
  - Mexico (R), 1990 -- 1991; UA027.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - MGU Correspondence (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Middlebury (R), 1988; UA027.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - NACB (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - [NAHHC Account Books], 1992 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - [NAHHC Annual Report, 1988-1989], 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - NAHHC General (Beginnings), 1985 -- 1986; UA027.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - [NAHHC Occasional Papers], 1992; UA027.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - New Network Production, Inc. (R), 1988; UA027.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - [Newspaper Clippings], 1989; UA027.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - NHK - TV (Japan) (R), 1990; UA027.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - NUTN (R), 1990; UA027.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - NYU - Journalism (R), 1989; UA027.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - [Photographs - Unidentified Events], 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Photos/Slides (R), 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Prince Alfred von Lichtenstein (R), 1991; UA027.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - Russia Info, 1988; UA027.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Political cartoon, US and USSR, "TV bridge", 1989; UA027.001.001.00073 (Box Shared 36)
    This poster was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials. Caption on poster: "To the constructors of the bridge with large sympathy." Author: Ceprei Wanupo
    poster
  - Telecast between Tufts University and Moscow State University, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00074 (Box Shared 36)
    This photograph was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials.
    photographic print
  - Telecast between Tufts University and Moscow State University, close-up of commentators, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00075 (Box Shared 36)
  - Martin Sherwin with unidentified men, Sardy House Hotel, photocopy, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00076 (Box Shared 36)
    This photocopy was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials.
  - Telecast between Tufts University and Moscow State University, close-up of man with microphone, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00077 (Box Shared 36)
  - Boston Globe article, "Satellite links Tufts, Soviet students for arms talks," photocopy, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00078 (Box Shared 36)
  - Collage of newspaper articles on television broadcasts between Tufts University and Moscow State University, photocopy, 1987; UA027.001.001.00079 (Box Shared 36)
  - Telecast between Tufts University and Moscow State University, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00080 (Box Shared 36)
    This poster was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials. Captions on poster: "Tufts, We'll Introduce You to the World." "A television 'space bridge' links class sessions between Tufts and Moscow State University."
  - Telecast between Tufts University and Moscow State University, 1987 -- 1988; UA027.001.001.00081 (Box Shared 36)
    Identical to item 80 except it is on posterboard. This item was found uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials.
  - A Russian festival of the arts, Tufts musical celebrity series, 1988; UA027.001.001.00082 (Box Shared 36)
    This item was found with the items 73-81; uncatalogued in the stacks in the summer of 2008. Note its different location; it is housed in a box with other oversized materials.
  - Talloires Newsltr. (R), 1988 -- 1989; UA027.001.002.00001 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - TPC - Sept 1988 (R), UA027.001.002.00002 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - TPC - Tokai (R), 1991 -- 1992; UA027.001.002.00003 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Tufts In Moscow, 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.002.00004 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - TUG Conference, July 1990 (R), UA027.001.002.00005 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - USA/USSR Course: Correspondence w/ Soviets, 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.002.00006 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - USA/USSR: Responses to Letters File, 1985 -- 1993; UA027.001.002.00007 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Global Classroom Project #2, 1988-04-09; UA027.001.004.00001 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS Fuji Tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00013, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #2, 1988-04-09; UA027.001.004.00002 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS Tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00014, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #2, 1988-04-09; UA027.001.004.00003 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Scotch Brand Name tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00015, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #3, 1988-04-30; UA027.001.004.00004 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00018, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #4, 1988-10-22; UA027.001.004.00005 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00021, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #5, 1988-12-10; UA027.001.004.00006 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00024, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #6, Tape 1, 1989-03-04; UA027.001.004.00007 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00027, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #6, Tape 2, 1989-03-04; UA027.001.004.00008 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00028, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #8, 1990-04-21; UA027.001.004.00009 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00034, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #9, 1991-04-20; UA027.001.004.00010 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00036, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #9, Tape 1, 1991-04-26; UA027.001.004.00011 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00037, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #10, Edited Version, 1991-11-02; UA027.001.004.00012 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00039, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #11, 1992-04-02; UA027.001.004.00013 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00045, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #11, Edited Version, 1992-04-04; UA027.001.004.00014 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    VHS, Fuji brand tape. A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00046, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the tape is stored here in box 4 of the collection.
  - Global Classroom Project #11, Slides, 1992; UA027.001.004.00015 (Box UA027 Shared 2)
    A surrogate folder, UA027/001-001/00043, exists as a placeholder at the item's original location. For preservation purposes, the slides are stored here in box 4 of the collection.
    slides
- Global Classroom Project Publicity Files, 1986 -- 1992; 1987 -- 1992; UA027.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials publicizing the GCP. Materials include press clippings, brochures, project proposals, flyers, and order forms for video tapes of individual GCP broadcasts. For related materials see also series 1.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically Originally, folders were filed according to a color coded system. The color tabs are indicated in parenthesis after the original folder title. Folders in this series were color coded blue (B).
  - 1 Page Flyer "Problem Solving" (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00008 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Brochure Samples (B), 1989 -- 1990; UA027.002.002.00009 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Early GCP 2 Page Flyer (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00010 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - EPU/MJS Blank Invites (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00011 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - GCP Folded Flyer (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00012 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - GCP Logos/Covers (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00013 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - GCP Press Clips (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00014 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - GCP Videotape Order Forms (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00015 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Global Classroom Press Clippings], 1987 -- 1989; UA027.002.002.00016 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Long Description (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00017 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Press Clips - Folded Flyer (B), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.002.002.00018 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Proposals (B), 1988 -- 1989; UA027.002.002.00019 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Proposal Samples (B), 1986; UA027.002.002.00020 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [U Foundation], 1989; UA027.002.002.00021 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Velikhov Support Letter (B), 1988; UA027.002.002.00022 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
- Martin Sherwin Subject Files, 1985 -- 1993; 1987 -- 1992; UA027.003; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials of Prof. Martin Sherwin, director of NAHHC. Included are correspondence with Tufts University President Jean Mayer and Vice Provost Sol Gittleman regarding the establishment of the NAHHC, drafts of grant proposals, research notes, and a video tape of the 1987 meeting of the Institute of East West Security Studies (IEWSS).
  Folders are arranged alphabetically. Originally, folders were filed according to a color coded system. The color tabs are indicated in parenthesis after the original folder title. Folders in this series were color coded white (W).
  - Annenberg Ctr. for Health Science (W), 1989; UA027.003.002.00023 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Baltic University (W), 1992; UA027.003.002.00024 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Beyond War (W), 1988; UA027.003.002.00025 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Bolkhovitinov, N. (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00026 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - CEM Correspondence (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00027 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Certificate for "Teleconferencing Going Global"], 1990; UA027.003.002.00028 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Citizen Exchange Council Conf. '87 (W), 1987; UA027.003.002.00029 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Computer/email Programming Directions, 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00030 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence w/ President Dibiaggio (W), 1992; UA027.003.002.00031 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence w/ Jean Mayer (W), 1986 -- 1992; UA027.003.002.00032 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Ellsburg - Cuban Missle Crisis, 1987; UA027.003.002.00034 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Emory University Lecture, 1989], UA027.003.002.00035 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - EPIIC (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00036 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Films - Nuclear (W), 1987; UA027.003.002.00037 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Gittleman Corresp. (W), 1991 -- 1992; UA027.003.002.00038 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Gontarev, Boris (W), 1989 -- 1991; UA027.003.002.00039 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - IAUP/UN (W), 1991; UA027.003.002.00040 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - IEWSS Meeting, Talloires [Video Tape], 1987; UA027.003.002.00041 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
    This folder is a surrogate folder. For preservation purposes, the VHS tape is stored seperately in box 4 of the collection
  - Institute For Security Studies (W), 1989; UA027.003.002.00042 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - IPPNW Correspondence (W), 1989 -- 1991; UA027.003.002.00043 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - IPRA (W), 1989; UA027.003.002.00044 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - ISKAN Correspond. (W), 1989 -- 1991; UA027.003.002.00045 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Kokoshin, A.], 1989; UA027.003.002.00046 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Kokoshin, Andrey (W), 1990 -- 1991; UA027.003.002.00047 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Kurchatov Inst. (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00048 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - List of Foreign Affairs/ Relations Organizations, 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00049 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - MA In Internat'l Studies (W), 1991; UA027.003.002.00050 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Medical - Russia (W), 1990 -- 1991; UA027.003.002.00051 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Moscow Conference], 1989; UA027.003.002.00052 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Moscow/June '89 Conference: Letters, Receipts, etc, 1989; UA027.003.002.00053 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - NAHC Speakers, 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00054 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - NAHC/ ISKAN Conf. June 1989 (W), UA027.003.002.00055 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
    This folder contains confidential information (passport numbers). It should be checked by the staff before use by a researcher.
  - The Nation / V. Navasky (W), 1991; UA027.003.002.00056 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Nuclear History Pro (Allen Greb) (W), 1992; UA027.003.002.00057 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - "Pearl Harbor" (W), 1991; UA027.003.002.00058 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Pleshakov, Kostya (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00059 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Poland, 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00060 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Political Cartoon], 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00061 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - [Research Notes], 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00062 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Russia Exchange Programs (W), 1990; UA027.003.002.00063 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Stanchenko, Vlad (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.002.00064 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - "Swords Into Plowshares" Conf. (W), 1990; UA027.003.002.00065 (Box UA027 Shared 1)
  - Tikhonov, Sergei (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.003.00001 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Trustees - Tufts (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.003.00002 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Tufts: IDOC Commit. (W), 1992; UA027.003.003.00003 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Tufts -USSR State Con ED. Agreement (W), 1990; UA027.003.003.00004 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Tufts Environ. Literacy Institute (W), 1991; UA027.003.003.00005 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - UPPSALA University, 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.003.00006 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - University of the World, 1992; UA027.003.003.00007 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Velikhov - "L.A. Program" Letter, UA027.003.003.00008 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Velikhov - Wed/May 17, 1985 -- 1989; UA027.003.003.00009 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Visiting Russian Delegation: 2/93, 1993; UA027.003.003.00010 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Will Keener (W), UA027.003.003.00011 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Working Papers (W), 1986 -- 1993; UA027.003.003.00012 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Yearbook 1990, UA027.003.003.00013 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - Zubok, Vladimir, 1990; UA027.003.003.00014 (Box UA027 Shared 3)
  - IEWSS Meeting, Talloires, 1987-10; UA027.003.004.00016 (Box UA027 Shared 2)